Finding Aid for the University at Buffalo Music Library Collection of Concert Programs, circa 1877-2009
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
University at Buffalo Music Library Collection of Concert Programs, circa 1877-2009
Mus. Arc. 91
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
13 boxes
The collection contains 13 boxes of concert programs, chiefly from England, but also including Buffalo, New York, and other cities in the United states, Austria, German, and other European countries, as well as Mexico and Canada.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Music Library through purchase and solicitation.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Historical Note
The collection was compiled from a combination of sources, including purchases from vendors and gifts from donors. Many of the programs are fairly rare, especially those from the 19th century.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains 13 boxes of concert programs, chiefly from England, but also including Buffalo, New York, and other cities in the United states, Austria, German, and other European countries, as well as Mexico and Canada.
Arrangement
The collection has been roughly sorted by geographic location of the performance.
Container List
- England. London. Royal Festival Hall, 1952-1960, 1 box (Box 1)
- England. London. Queen's Hall and Wigmore Hall, 1895-1956, 1 box (Box 2)
- England. London. Royal Philharmonic and London Philharmonic Societies, 1877-1961, 1 box (Box 3)
- England. London. London Symphony Orchestra, 1907-1961, 1 box (Box 4)
- England. London. Various venues, undated, 1 box (Box 5)
- England. Varied locations, undated, 1 box (Box 6)
- Austria, 1932-1955, 1 box (Box 7)
- Germany. Varied locations, unsorted programs, undated, 1 box (Box 8)
- Other European countries, Mexico, Canada, and Jerusalem, undated, 1 box (Box 9)
  European countries include Belgium, France, Monaco, Netherlands, Sweden, and Switzerland.
- United States. New York. Buffalo, Lewiston, and Rochester, undated, 1 box (Box 10)
- United States. New York. New York and Boston, Massachusetts, undated, 1 box (Box 11)
- United States. Various locations, undated, 1 box (Box 12)
- Tour program booklets without specific performance venues, undated, 1 box (Box 10)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Concert programs--19th century; Concert programs--20th century
Genres
Concert programs